and I have been asked by developers and
non-developers what is the best way to
get started and where to study if I want
to work on AI I am by no means an AI
expert but I have done my fair share of
studying because I wanted to understand
how this AI thing that looks like magic
actually worked behind the scenes the
thing is that I found that the process
of learning AI by myself a bit
intimidating at first because many
courses are either paid and expensive
they are a bit too advanced for
beginners and they assume a lot of
previous knowledge making it easy to get
frustrated overwhelmed and to give up so
today I want to share with you a couple
of resources I used when learning AI
that are free not intimidating and
perfect for beginners One requirement to
be able to take these courses is that
you should be comfortable riding python
code python is the language of AI so it
is a must the good news is that learning
python is easy and you can learn it in
our website for free
most of these resources are in English
since English is the language of the
internet but don't worry because there
is also a resource in Han Google as well
the course where I point everyone that
asks me how to learn AI is practical
deep learning for coders practical deep
learning for coders is an incredible
free course for people that have
experience in programming but not in
machine learning with practical deep
learning for colors you can go from
knowing how to make websites to knowing
how to build your own neural networks
from scratch the course consists of 990
minute video lessons but in case you
like reading more than watching there is
also a book that you can buy in Amazon
if you want to support the project or
you can read it online for free as well
the course was recently fully
re-recorded in 2022 and it is taught by
Jeremy Howard he is the lead developer
of fast Ai and he is the president and
chief scientist of kaggle this course is
taught following a top-down approach
which basically means that you learn how
to drive the car first and then later
you learn how the engine actually works
instead of starting with Theory first
and then having to push until the end to
see it all come together in this course
you first start with the big picture
seeing how to train models with your own
data and how to deploy them as web
applications after that you learn the
details and how it all works behind the
scenes and then you end up writing a
whole model by yourself using pi torch
you also don't need Harker math to get
started the linear algebra and the
calculus you will need are taught inside
of the course after you're done with
that course I then suggest checking out
neural networks from Zero to Hero by the
legend himself Andre carpati he is the
former director of AI at Tesla and he is
one of the founding members of openai
the company behind Dali and chat GPT
this is a course that shows you how to
build neural networks from scratch in
Python with a special focus on language
models at the time of recording this
video this course is still ongoing
meaning there might be more lectures to
come so far there are seven lectures
with the latest one being an almost two
hour video where you build your own GPT
from scratch and you teach it to write
in the style of Shakespeare for
transparency I do have to say that I
haven't watched all the lectures because
of time constraints but from the First
videos I can tell that Andrea's teaching
style is so cool and he knows the
subject so well that you will be hooked
after watching the first video that's
for sure the two courses I just
mentioned follow the style of learning
by doing which I think is the best way
to learn nothing is better than getting
your hands dirty and ending up with a
final product another great way to study
AI is to apply to the year during school
which is also a sponsor of this video
the ministry of smes and startups and
Korea smes and startups agency are
recruiting 200 people to join a free AI
education program called a year dream
school year dream School runs for 10
months and it teaches you from the very
basics of programming to the advanced
level such as data engineering machine
learning and deep learning it is an
intensive AI education program that is
almost equivalent to attending a
four-year college with a major in AI all
of these 10 months of Education are
completely free anyone under 39 years
old that is eager to learn can apply
regardless of his or her education level
or career background you don't even have
to pass a coding test on the selection
process is one of the shortest Pathways
for non-majors to become AI developers
within a promotion for year dream school
last year as well this is their third
year running the program year dream
school not only does the training but
also help students getting a job or
making their own startup as well
application is open right now so please
check out the link below thank you for
watching as always
see you on the next one bye
thank you